Guide to the Border Service Department of the Church of Christ in China Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Border Service Department of the Church of Christ in China Records
1932-1984
RG 17
Yale University Divinity School Library
2
(4 boxes)
The records provide valuable documentation of an indigenous program of the church in China during the years 1939 to 1950. The correspondence and writings of Archie R. Crouch, English-language secretary of the Department, 1944-1946, provide interesting insight into the experiences of a Western missionary serving under Chinese leadership. The Border Service Department was the first missionary outreach effort of the Chinese Church. The peoples among whom the Border Service Department worked were known as the Kiang or Ch'iang, Chiarong or Gia-rung, Lolos or Nosus, and Miaos. Fields of work were western Szechuan (Lifan), Sikong and Yunnan.
Zhonghua ji du jiao hui. Border Service Dept
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Archie Crouch.
Biographical / Historical
In 1939, the Church of Christ in China requested permission from the government to do educational and medical work among certain ethnic groups on China's western border. There was a growing tendency to view ethnic groups as a threat to national unity in China during the 1930s, so the government eagerly accepted the Church's proposal. An agreement was made that the government would provide certain equipment and the Church would provide the staff. The Border Service Department was the first missionary outreach effort of the Chinese Church.
Cheng Ching Yi, General Secretary of the Church of Christ in China, conceived the plan for a Border Service Department but died before the Department was established. William B. Djang (Djang Po-huai), former Dean at Cheeloo University, served as General Secretary of the Department from 1939 to 1949. Some Western missionaries served under the Border Service Department, but the staff was primarily Chinese. Archie R. Crouch, missionary of the Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A., spent two years (1944-1946) as English-language secretary on the staff of the Border Service Department. It is through him that these papers of the Border Service Department have been gathered and preserved. Crouch remained in contact with Chinese leaders of the Border Service Department for many years after his return to the United States. The Department was disbanded following the Communist liberation of China.
The peoples among whom the Border Service Department worked were known as the Kiang or Ch'iang, Chiarong or Gia-rung, Lolos or Nosus, and Miaos. Fields of work were western Szechuan (Lifan), Sikong and Yunnan. The Department cooperated with other agencies in carrying out educational, medical and agricultural work. During World War II, a project was carried out in conjunction with the United States Army to educate Lolo people regarding the treatment of airmen who were forced to bail out of their planes into Lolo territory.
By 1949, nearly one hundred staff members of the Border Service Department were at work among the border ethnic groups, in primary schools, medical centers, agricultural stations, hostels for travelers, and industry projects.
Scope and Contents
These records provide valuable documentation of an indigenous program of the church in China during the years 1939 to 1950. The correspondence and writings of Archie R. Crouch also provide interesting insight into the experiences of a Western missionary serving under Chinese leadership. Crouch was English-language secretary of the Department in China 1944-1946; he continued to promote the Department and correspond with its leaders after his return to the United States.
Series I, REPORTS AND OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS, contains administrative memos, reports, records of the Board of Directors, budget information, and other material documenting the program and operations of the Border Service Department. Arranged chronologically, these records provide a thorough overview of the work of the Department during the years 1940 to 1949.
Series II, CORRESPONDENCE, contains primarily the correspondence of Archie R. Crouch and William B. Djang (Djang Po-huai). Crouch served as a liaison between the Chinese leaders of the Border Service Department and its Western supporters. His regular, detailed report letters and other correspondence provide important documentation of the work of the
Department. Particularly valuable are the substantive letters exchanged between Crouch and William B. Djang.
Series III, WRITINGS/PUBLICATIONS, includes typescript and published materials on a variety of topics relating to the work of the Border Service Department. Some of the writings specifically describe programs of the Department while others provide background regarding the ethnic groups served by the Department.
Series IV, SLIDES, includes approximately sixty well-labeled black and white slides which portray scenes and customs of China's western borders.
Arrangement
I. Reports and Official Documents, 1940-1949, n.d.
II. Correspondence, 1935-1984, n.d.
III. Writings, Publications, 1932-1949, n.d.
IV. Slides, 1944-1946
Missions -- China; Crouch, Archie R.; Djang, Po-huai; Zhonghua Jidu jiao hui. Bian jiang fu wu bu
- Reports and Official Documents, 1940-1949, n.d.; Series I
  - "C.C.C. Border Missions Budget", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Some News Items of Border Mission", ca. 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "1942 - The Eventful Year in Border Evangelism" by W.B. Djang, ca. 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The 1943 Summer Missionary Work of the Border Mission", ca. 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Project for Research of Lolo Religion", ca. 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "An Address of Dr. H.H. Kung to the Border MissionCommittee at its Fifth Annual Meeting", 1943 Oct 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Remarks of Mr. Huang Yen Pei on the Border Mission - Fifth Annual Meeting, Chungking", 1943 Oct 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Social Rehabilitation in the Sungpan-Lifan Area under the Auspices of the Border Mission", ca. 1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Extracts from a letter of Mr. H.D. Tsui, Field Director of the Lifan Mission", 1944 Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "With God Nothing is Impossible" - report of W.B. Djang, 1944 Dec 31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "A Report of the Border Service Work - 1944"- by W.B. Djang, ca. 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "An Experiment in Close Cooperation between the Government Public Health Administration and the Border Service Hospital in Sichang", 1945 Jun 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "A Memorandum on the Work of the Border Service Department", 1945 Sep 20 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Memorandum on the War Service Projects in the Estimate budget for 1946, ca. 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Report on the Work of the Border Mission", 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes - Committee on Aid to Social Workers, International Relief Committee, Chungking, 1946 Feb 6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "A Memorandum of the Border Service Department", 1946 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Conference between Drs. Tsui, Fisher and Mr. W. B. Djang, 1946 Jul (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes - Standing Committee of the CCC, 1946 Nov 8 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "A Memo on Border Mission", ca. 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Project Requests from the Border Mission of the Church of Christ in China - Submitted to United China Relief for 1946" (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - List of Board of Directors of B.S.D., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Summary B.S.D. 1947 Budget, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "A Memo on the Border Mission" by W.B. Djang, 1947 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Minutes of a Special Meeting of the General Committee of the Border Mission of the Church of Christ in China (The Nanking Section)", 1948 Jun 10 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Circular letter from C.T. Tsai, Secretary for National Missions, Church of Christ in China, 1949 Nov 18 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Constitution of the Border Missions Commission", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Evangelistic Work of the Border Mission of the G.A. of the C.C.C.", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Report on a Visit to the Border Mission" [by Archie R. Crouch], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Tengchung Report", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Project for a Survey of Christian Work among Yunnan Tribes People", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "War Service Project for the Lolos of the Liangshan Region", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "A List of Audio-visual Education Equipment for the B.S.D. of the C.C.C.", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "The Medical Staff of the Border Mission", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Staff of the Sikong Hospital of the B.S.D.", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Suggestions for an Institute of Cultural Research", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "The Border Research Institute", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Books and Magazines Wanted by the B.S.D." (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Special Program", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Financial statement form, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chinese language report of Border Mission actions re.budget and personnel (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Outline of Sino-Tibetan Relations from 700-1946 (Archie Crouch) (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Post-war student incidents in China, 1948 Jul (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Christmas in Zakulao (Mildred Stray); A Chinese Village (Martin Yang), n.d., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Leadership for the Unfinished Battle (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Present work: Future Plans for the Border Service Department, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - General Principals for a Project of Community Improvement in Southern Yunnan, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Hymns in the Himalayas, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Suggestions re: the relationships between the Presbyterian Mission in China: The Church of Christ Mission, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - The Future of Theological Education in China, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Annual Report of the Church of Christ in China - New Plan for 1946, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Questionnaire (Archie Crouch) and article (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Correspondence, 1935-1984, n.d; Series II
  - Correspondence of Archie R. Crouch
    - British Information Services, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - British Ministry of Information- re. missing photographs of Lolo life and culture, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Broomhall, A. J. (China Inland Mission), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Clarke, Hal, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Connibear, A. A., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Coonradt, Ralph, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Copland, E. Bruce, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Cranstoun, Margaret, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Crouch report letters to supporters in the U.S., 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
    - Crouch circular letter, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Crouch letters of acknowledgement for financial support of Border Service Department and re. speaking engagements in U.S., 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 17-20)
    - Djang, William B. (Djang Po-huai), 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 21-26)
    - Dye, Daniel S., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Fisher, A. J., 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Henderson-Smith, J., 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Ho Chao-fan, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Hsu, C. L., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Jiang Wen-han (Kiang Wen Han), incl. letter re. his death from wife, Yao Hsien hwei, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Lautenschlager, Stanton, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Ling, Frank, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Liu, Grace, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Liu Lin-chiu (re. Den Shu Kao, Eastman Dental Dispensary), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - [Liu?], Samuel, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Oliver, George, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Outerbridge, T. S. (International Relief Committee), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Ruland (Presbyterian Church USA), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Tootell, George, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Tsui, David and Mildred, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Tsui, Henry D., 1947-1950, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Tsui, H. H. (Hiram), 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 31A)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture - re. kudzu seed, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Williamson, H. R. (Baptist Missionary Society) - re. Crouch photos of Lolos, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Wu, C. Jean Wang, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Unidentified, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Chinese language and Lolo script letters of thanks for Christmas gifts, to Archie Crouch and family from school children, 1937?, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence of William B. Djang (Djang Po-huai)
    - British Ministry of Information - re. Crouch photos of Lolos, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Cadbury, Branden (Friends' Ambulance Unit) - re. Tengchung hospital proposition in Yunnan, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Chung, Mr. (Border School at Nan Wen Chuan), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Copland, E. Bruce, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Djang, Y. S. (International Relief Committee) - with Chinese language enclosures re. B.S.D. grant request, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Drake, F. S., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Edwards, Dwight (United China Relief), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Fisher, Hiram, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Haines, H. - re. criticism of B.S.D., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Henderson-Smith, J., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Jolt (?), Curtis M., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Moncrieff, J. E. (American Baptist Missionary Society), 1945 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Mortensen, Ralph (Society of Friends of Moslems in China), 1945 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Outerbridge, T. S. (International Relief Committee), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Rees, Ronald (Djang statement on future of missionary work in China), 1944 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Tsui, Henry D., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Williamson, H. R. (Baptist Missionary Society), 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Other correspondence
    - Two circular letters of Bill and Win Upchurch from Sichang, Sikang, W. China, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Photostatic copies of 3 letters in Chinese and Tibetan, with translations, asking the Border Service to open a hospital in Cho k'e-chi, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Unidentified Chinese language letter (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Letter of Ernest G. T. Madge to H. H. Tsui, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous - alphabetized (Box 2, Folder 39a)
- Writings/ Publications, 1932-1949, n.d; Series III
  - Published material
    - Chinese language handbook of the Border Service Department; published by the headquarters of the B.S.D. in Chengtu (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Chinese language serial: Pien-chiang fu-wu (Border Work) - seven issues, 1943, 1944, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Chinese language: Plans to return to home regions from wartime headquarters and stations in West China (Church of Christ in China, Chungking), 1945 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Chinese language: The Future of China by Chiang Kai-shek, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Chinese language: Essay on Ta Yu, early emperor of China, who was born in Wen Chuen, Szechuan; gazeteer type description of the county, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Chinese language:A brief history of Wen Chuen county by the magistrate of the county, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - China's Wild West; pamphlet published by the Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. [by Archie R. Crouch], 1949 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - "The Christian Front in China": series of articles by Archie R. Crouch; published weekly in The Church Times, 1944 Jul-1947 Jun (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - The Church and the Future in China - National Christian Council of China memorandum, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Important Actions of the Enlarged General Council Meeting of the General Assembly of the Church of Christ in China, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Typescript material re. China and B.S.D.
    - "After Six Years - Yunnan, our Newest Mission", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "The Border Missions of the Church of Christ in China", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "The Challenge of China's North-west", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "Cheeloo School of Theology Refresher Course Report" by F. S. Drake, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "Cheng Kiang Senior Middle School Return to its Old Campus" by Archie R. Crouch, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "China's Wild West" by ARC, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "Chinese Christians Sing to Your Boys" by ARC, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "The Churches in the West and the Rehabilitation of the Church in China" (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "Forecast of Possible Developments in Post-War China That Will Affect the Church", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "Forward Station" by ARC, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "General Plan for the TRAIL BLAZERS Work of the Border Mission", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "Hymns of the Himalayas" by ARC, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Interview re. work of Border Services Department, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "A New Challenge to the Border Mission", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "A New Age for Christian Missions in China" by Archie R. Crouch; letters of evaluation of manuscript by Elizabeth H.S. Murray, Gordon Jones, and Daniel Dye attached, ca. 1945 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "The Next Step is Tibet" by ARC, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "An Oasis in a Vast Human Desert: the Story of the Border Mission of the Church of Christ in China" by William B. Djang (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - "An Open Letter fo Young People Who Have Attended Conferences this Summer' by ARC, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - "Out Beyond" by ARC (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - "A Prospectus for Missionary Work among the Wild Lolos", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - "Relief and Rebuilding of Hsing Wen Ping", ca. 1945 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - "Spiritual Needs of the Churches and Evangelism", 1946 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - "Stories of Experiences of the Border Mission Workers", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - "This is Not the Time to Kick" by ARC, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - "The Work of the Border Mission of the Church of Christ in China" - a broadcast address, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Untitled and brief texts (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Typescript material related to ethnic groups of China
    - "The Decline and Possible Future of a Great Race: the Ch'iang People" by William B. Djang (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - "Ethnobotany of the Gia-rung Tribe" by S.Y. Hu, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - "An Outline of the Ethnography of China" by Archie R. Crouch; Printed map enclosed: "Distribution and Classification of the South-west Aboriginal Tribe in China", 1948 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - English translation by Archie R. Crouch of Chapters I and II of "The Facts About the Lolos" by Ling Kwang-tien (Kai Ming Book Co. Chengtu, Sze., 1943) (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - "Why a Daugher-in-Law Avoids Her Father-in-law and Her Brothers-in-law" by Archie R. Crouch - re. Lolo custom, No date (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Other typescript writings
    - "Mothers of the Army" by ARC, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 53A)
    - "Teaching Religion at Home" by ARC, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 53A)
- Slides, 1944-1946; Series IV
  - Box of 35mm slides labeled "Border Service Outposts - Chia-shan-chai, Jih-er-chueh, and others"; 60 slides documenting Chia-shan-chai folk dancers, agriculture, symbols, jewelry, clothing, buildings, houses, grave pottery, Nestorian cross, opium patients, bamboo bridge, f irecracker, Lama temple, educational and religious work, etc. (Box 3, Folder 55)